const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",o="chemistry",t=200,i=120,a=[{id:105,question:"Metals of the first transition series have special proper ties which are different from those of groups I and II elements because they have partially filled",option:{a:"s  orbitals",b:"p orbitals",c:"d orbitals",d:"f orbitals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:113,question:"Carbohydrates are compounds containing carbon, hydrogen and oxygen in the ratio",option:{a:"3:01:01",b:"2:01:01",c:"1:02:01",d:"1:01:01"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:269,question:"Elements in the same periodic table have the same",option:{a:"Atomic number",b:"Chemical properties",c:"Physical properties",d:"Number of shells"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:256,question:"Which of the following typically represents a photochemical reaction",option:{a:"Conversion of dinitrogen (IV) oxide to nitrogen(IV) oxide",b:"Conversion of silver halides to grey metallic silver",c:"Decomposition of calcium hydroxide to its oxide",d:"Formation of water from hydrogen and oxygen molecules"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:39,question:"The pair of organic compounds that are isomers is",option:{a:"Benzene and methylbenzene",b:"Trichloromethane and Tetrachloromethane",c:"Ethanol and propanone",d:"But-1-ene and but-2-ene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:287,question:"2H2(g) +    O2(g)  ⇌ 2H2O(g)    ΔH   =  - ve  What happens to the equilibrium constant of the reaction above if the temperature is increased?",option:{a:"It becomes zero",b:"It decreases",c:"It increases",d:"It is unaffected"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:99,question:"When at equilibrium, which of the reactions below will shift to the right if the pressure is increased and the temperature is kept constant",option:{a:" 2SO3(g)  ⇌  2SO2(g)  +  O2(g)",b:" 2CO2(g)  ⇌ 2CO(g)  +  O2(g)",c:" 2H2(g)  +  O2(g) ⇌  2H2O(g)",d:" 2NO(g)   ⇌ N2(g)  +  O2(g)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:206,question:"The gas that is the most dangerous pollutant to humans is",option:{a:"Carbon(IV) oxide",b:"Nitrogen (II)oxide",c:"Hydrogen sulphide",d:"Sulphur(IV) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:143,question:"ZnO(s) + CO (g) → Zn(s) + CO2 (g). ",option:{a:"Decomposed",b:"Displaced",c:"Oxidized",d:"Reduced"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:96,question:"The commonest feature of the reactions at the anode is that",option:{a:"Electrons are consumed",b:"Oxidation is involved",c:"Ions are reduced",d:"Electrode dissolves"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:116,question:"The formula for ethyl butanoate is",option:{a:"C3H7COOC2H5",b:"C2H5COOC3H7",c:"C4H9COOC2H5",d:"C2H5COOC4H9"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:165,question:"Vulcanization involves the removal of",option:{a:"A monomer",b:"The single bond",c:"The double bond",d:"A polymer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:159,question:"Sodium metal is always kept under oil because it",option:{a:"Readily reacts with water",b:"Is reduced by atmospheric nitrogen",c:"Reacts vigorously on exposure to air",d:"Reacts with oxygen and carbon(IV) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:15,question:"The chemiocal used for coagulation in water purification is",option:{a:"Aluminum tetraoxosulphate(VI)",b:"Copper tetratoxosulphate (VI)",c:"Sodium tetraoxosulphate(VI)",d:"Calcium tetraoxosulphate (VI)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:293,question:"Stainless steel is used for making",option:{a:"Tools",b:"Coins and medals",c:"Moving parts of clocks",d:"Magnets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:24,question:" 2SO2(g) + O2(g) ⇌  2SO3(g)  The equilibrium constant for the reaction above is increased by  [ΔH = -189kJ mol -1]",option:{a:"Increasing the temperature of the system",b:"Increasing the pressure of the system",c:"The addition of a catalyst to the system",d:"Increasing the surface area of the vessel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:135,question:"Hardness of water is caused by the presence of the ions of",option:{a:"Magnesium and silver",b:"Calcium and magnesium",c:"Sodium and potassium",d:"Calcium and sodium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:20,question:"Which of the following best explains the increase in the rate of a chemical reaction as the temperature rises",option:{a:"The bonds in the reacting molecules are more readily broken",b:"The molecules collisions become more violent",c:"A lower proportion of the molecules has the necessary minimum energy to react",d:"The collision frequency of the molecules increases"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:4,question:"Cancerous growths are cured by exposure to",option:{a:"ɣ-rays",b:" β – rays",c:" ἀ – rays",d:"X -rays"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:41,question:"The gas that can best be collected by downward displacement of air is",option:{a:"Chlorine",b:"Sulphur(IV)oxide",c:"Ammonia",d:"Carbon(IV)oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:290,question:"A constituent common to moist air, it gradually rusts. This is due to the formation of",option:{a:"Silver",b:"Copper",c:"Tin",d:"Lead"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:149,question:" N2O4(g)    ⇌  2NO2(g)",option:{a:"A constant volume",b:"An increase in pressure",c:"A decrease in pressure",d:" A decrease in volume"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:277,question:"Calculate the volume of 0.5 mol dm-3 H2SO4 that is neutralized by 25cm3 of 0.1 mol dm-3 NaOH",option:{a:"2.5cm3",b:"0.4cm3",c:"0.1cm3",d:"5.0cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:248,question:"An emulsion may be produced by shaking a detergent solution with",option:{a:"Palm wine",b:"Palm oil",c:"Ethanoic acid",d:"Water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:86,question:"The weakest attractive force that can be observed between two molecules is",option:{a:"Ionic",b:"Covalent",c:"Coordinate covalent",d:"Van der Waals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:85,question:"When cathode rays are detected onto the electrode of an electrometer, the instrument becomes",option:{a:"Negatively charged",b:"Positively charged",c:"Neutral",d:"Bipolar"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:191,question:"The component of an atom that contributes least to its mass is the",option:{a:"Nucleus",b:"Neutron",c:"Electron",d:"Proton"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:54,question:"The furring of kettles is caused by the presence in water of",option:{a:"Calcium trioxocarbonate(IV)",b:"Calcium tetraoxosulphate(VI)",c:"CALCIUM HYDROXIDE",d:"Calcium hydrofentrioxocarbonate(IV)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:68,question:"A rock sample was added to cold dilute HNMO3. The gas evolved was passed into a solution of acidified K2Cr2O7 and the solution turned green. The rock sample contains",option:{a:"NO3-",b:"Cl-",c:"SO42-",d:"SO32-"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:241,question:"Nigerian crude oil is described as light crude because of its",option:{a:"Low aliphatic hydrocarbon content",b:"Low sulphur content",c:"High natural gas content",d:"High octane number"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:229,question:"[Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p + 22.4dm3} Nuclear fission involves the splitting of a heavy element into two nuclei of",option:{a:"Equal masses with a release of energy",b:"Nearly equal masses with a release of energy and radiation",c:"Equal masses with a release of energy and radiation",d:"Unequal masses without any release of energy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:147,question:` 2CO(g)  +  O2(g) →  2CO2(g)
Given that   Δ H [CO] is 110.4kJ mol-1 and Δ H [CO2] is -393.0kJ mol-1, the energy change for the reaction above is
`,option:{a:"-503.7kJ",b:"-282.6kJ",c:"+282.6kJ",d:"+503.7kJ"},section:"",image:"",answer:"N",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:111,question:"The modern process of manufacturing steel from iron is by",option:{a:"Treatment with acids",b:"Oxidation",c:"Blast reduction",d:"Treatment with alkalis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:238,question:"An example of aliphatic unsaturated hydrocarbon is",option:{a:"Butanol",b:"Propene",c:"Pentane",d:"Benzene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:175,question:"N2(g)  +  3H2(g)  ⇌   2NH2(g)   Δ H = - 90kJ  In the equation above, the yield of ammonia can be decreased by",option:{a:"Adding a catalyst",b:"Removing ammonia",c:"Increasing the pressure",d:"Increasing the temperature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:180,question:"When pure aluminum metal is heated to red hot in the presence of nitrogen gas, the compound formed is",option:{a:"AI2N",b:"AIN",c:"AI2N2",d:"AI2N3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:270,question:"A noble gas with a high power of fog penetration used in aerodrome beacons is",option:{a:"Argon",b:"Helium",c:"Neon",d:"Krypton"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:284,question:"In which of the following is the entropy change positive",option:{a:"Reaction between an acid and a base",b:"Addition of concentrated acid to water",c:"Dissolution of sodium metal in water",d:"Thermal dissociation of ammonium chloride"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:164,question:"Which of these reagents can confirm the presence of a triple bond",option:{a:"Bromine water",b:"Acidified KMnO4 ",c:"Copper (I) chloride",d:"Bromine gas"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:264,question:"The volume of a gas is Vcm3 at P mm Hg. What is the new volume of the gas if the pressure is reduced to half at constant temperature",option:{a:"2 V cm3",b:"V  2cm3",c:"V cm3",d:"4 V cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:126,question:"What volume of gas is evolved at s.t.p. if 2g of calcium trioxocarbonate(IV) is added to a solution of hydrochloric acid    [Ca = 40, C = 12, O = 16, CI = 35.5, H = 1, Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4dm3]",option:{a:"112cm3",b:"224cm3",c:"448cm3",d:"224cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:162,question:"An isomer of C5H12 is",option:{a:"Butane",b:"2-methylbutane",c:"2-methylprpane",d:"2-ethylbutane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:92,question:"Farmlands affected by crude –oil spillage can be decontaminated by",option:{a:"Adding acidic solutions",b:"Using aerobic bacteria",c:"Pouring water on the affected area",d:"Burning off the oil from the area"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:78,question:"The filter in a cigarette reduces the nicotine content by",option:{a:"Burning",b:"Adsorption",c:"Evaporation",d:"Absorption"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:87,question:"A consequence of global warming is",option:{a:"Air pollution",b:"Water pollution",c:"Increased humidity",d:"Flooding"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:301,question:"One of the major uses of Alkanes is",option:{a:"In the hydrogenation of oils",b:"In the textile industries",c:"In the production of plastics",d:"As domestic and industrial fuels"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:31,question:"The general formula for the alkanals is",option:{a:"ROH",b:"R2CO",c:"RCOOR1",d:"RCHO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:16,question:"Phosphorous is stored under water to precvent it from",option:{a:"Dehydrating",b:"Becoming inert",c:"Smelling",d:"Catching fire"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:300,question:"The correct order of increasing boiling points of the following  compounds C3H7OH, C7H16 and C4H10 is",option:{a:"C4H10  →  C7H16 → C3H7OH",b:"C7H16 → C3H7OH → C4H16",c:"C4H10  → C3H7OH  → C4H10",d:"C3H7OH →  C4H10  → C7H16"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:220,question:"Trioxonitrate(V) acid is not used for preparing hydrogen gas from metals because it",option:{a:"Renders the metal passive",b:"Is strongly oxidizing",c:"Is volatile",d:""},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:280,question:"6AgNO3(aq)  +  PH3(g) +    3H2O(l)      →    6Ag(s)+   H3PO3(aq)   +    6HNO3(aq)  In the reaction above, the reducing agent is",option:{a:"H2O(l)",b:"PH3(g)",c:"AgNO3(aq)",d:"HNO3(AQ)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:60,question:"which of the following chlorides would exhibit the least ionic character",option:{a:"AlCl3",b:"CaCl2",c:"MgCi2",d:"LiCl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:26,question:"When ΔH is negative, a reaction is said to be",option:{a:"Ionic",b:"Reversible",c:"Exothermic",d:"Endothermic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:218,question:"The ion that can be used as an oxidizing agent is",option:{a:"Fe3+",b:"F-",c:"Ca2+",d:"Au3+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:260,question:"Which of he following pairs of substances will react further with oxygen to form a higher oxide",option:{a:"SO2 and NO",b:"CO2 and H2O",c:"CO and CO2",d:"NO and H2O"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:35,question:"A trihydric alkanol is",option:{a:"glycerol",b:"phenol",c:"glycol",d:"ethanol"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:197,question:"A substance that is used as a ripening agent for fruits is",option:{a:"Propene",b:"Methane",c:"Ethene",d:"Butane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:200,question:"Natural water collected from rivers and ponds contains oxygen, carbon(IV) oxide and",option:{a:"Chlorine",b:"Hydrogen",c:"Sulphur(IV) oxide",d:"Nitrogen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:94,question:"A charge in the temperature of a saturated solution disturbs the equilibrium between the",option:{a:"Dissolved solute and the solvent",b:"Solvent and the undissolved solute",c:"Dissolved solute and the undissolved solute",d:"Dissolved solute and the solution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:32,question:"The main impurity in iron ore during the extraction of iron is",option:{a:"Silicon (IV) oxide",b:"Carbon(IV) oxide",c:"Calciumtrioxosilicate",d:"Sulphur(II) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:11,question:"Deliquenscent substances are used for",option:{a:"Cooling",b:"Wetting",c:"Melting",d:"Drying"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:225,question:"The solution that will conduct the highest amount of electricity is",option:{a:"2.0 moldm-3 of ethanoic acid",b:"0.5 mol dm-3 of ethanoic acid",c:"2.0 mol dm-3 of hydrochloric acid",d:"0.5 moldm-3 of hydrochloric acid"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:64,question:"A gas X diffuses twice as fast as gas Y under the same conditions. If the relative molecular mass of X is 28. Calculate the relative molecular mass of Y",option:{a:"120",b:"14",c:"56",d:"112"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:196,question:"In the purification of impure samples of ethyl ethanoate synthesized by esterification, concentrated sodium trioxocarbonate(IV) solution is used to remove",option:{a:"Water",b:"Acidic impurities",c:"Basic impurities",d:"Ethoxyethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:297,question:"Benzene reacts with hydrogen in the presence of nickel catalyst at 1800C to give",option:{a:"Toluene",b:"Cyclopentane",c:"Cyclohexane",d:"Xylene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:282,question:"Iron can be protected from corrosion by coating the surface with",option:{a:"Silver",b:"Copper",c:"Zinc",d:"Gold"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:62,question:"The processes which return carbon(IV) oxide to the atmosphere include",option:{a:"Photosynthesis, decay and respiration",b:"Photosynthesis, respiration and transpiration",c:"Respiration, decay and combustion",d:"Ozone, depletion, combustion and decay"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:240,question:"CH3-CH2-C = CH  The hybridization in the compound above is",option:{a:"Sp3 and sp",b:"Sp3 and sp2",c:"Sp",d:"Sp2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:138,question:"The solubility in mol dm-3 of 20g of CuSO4 dissolved in 100g of water at 1800C is  [Cu = 64, S = 32, O = 16]",option:{a:"0.13",b:"0.25",c:"1.25",d:"2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:298,question:"Which of the following is used to hasten the ripening of fruit",option:{a:"Ethanol",b:"Ethyne",c:"Ethane",d:"Ethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:2,question:"What mass of water is produced when 8.0g of hydriogen reacts with excess oxygen [H = 1, O = 16]",option:{a:"36.0g",b:"8.0g",c:"72.0g",d:"16.0g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:110,question:"Chlorine gas turns a damp starch-iodide paper",option:{a:"Pink",b:"Colourless",c:"Red",d:"Dark blue"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:210,question:"When sulphur (IV) oxide is passed into a solution of sodium hydroxide for a long time. It eventually produces a solution of",option:{a:"Na2SO4",b:"NaHSO4",c:"Na2SO3",d:"NaHSO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:52,question:"The substance least considered as a source of environmental pollution is",option:{a:"Silicate minerals",b:"Uranium",c:"Lead compounds",d:"Organophosphorous compounds"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:153,question:"Which steam is passed over red-hot carbon, the substances produced are",option:{a:"Hydrogen and trioxocarbonate(IV) acid",b:"Hydrogen, oxygen and carbon(IV) oxide",c:"Hydrogen and carbon (II) oxide",d:"Hydrogen and carbon (IV) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:251,question:"The raw material used for the smelting of iron ore in a furnace is",option:{a:"Zn(NO3)2",b:"CaSO4",c:"CuSO4",d:"CaCO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:174,question:"To obtain pure carbon(II) oxide from its mixture with carbon (IV)oxide, the mixture should be",option:{a:"Bubbled through concentrated Tetraoxosulphate(VI) acid",b:"Bubbled through sodium hydroxide",c:"Passed over heated copper(II) oxide",d:"Bubbled through water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:211,question:"What is the correct IUPAC name for NO2",option:{a:"Dioxonitrate(III) ion",b:"Dioxonitrate(IV) ION",c:"trioxonitrate(iii) ion",d:"trioxonitrate(iv) ion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:9,question:"Which of the following statements is correct about the average kinetic energy of the molecules of a gas",option:{a:"It inctreasaes with increase in pressure",b:"It increases at constant pressure",c:"It increases with increase in temperature",d:"It increases in volume"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:72,question:"The intermediate product formed when ethanol is progressively oxidized to ethanoic acid with potassium heptaoxodichromate(VI) is",option:{a:"Ethanol",b:"Methanol",c:"Butanal",d:"Propanal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:129,question:"A given volume of methane diffuses in 20s. how long will it take the same volume of sulphur(IV) oxide to diffuse under the same conditions    [C = 12, H = 1, S = 32, O = 16]",option:{a:"5s",b:"20s",c:"40s",d:"60s"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:83,question:` I.  H = 1s1
II. O = 1s22s22p4
III. N = 1s22s22p3
IV. Zn = 1s22s22p63s23p64s23d10
From the above, which of the following pairs is likely to be paramagnetic?
`,option:{a:"I and II",b:"I and  III",c:"I    and IV",d:"III  and IV"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:66,question:"The postulate of Dalton’s atomic theory which still holds is that",option:{a:"Particles of different elements combine in a simple whole number ratio",b:"Atoms can neither be created nor destroyed",c:"The particles of the same element are exactly alike",d:"All elements are made of small indivisible particles"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:156,question:"Aluminium hydroxide is used in the dyeing industry as a",option:{a:"Salt",b:"Dye",c:"Mordant",d:"Dispersant"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:100,question:"In the electrolysis of a concentrated solution of sodium chloride using inert electrodes, which of the following ions are discharged at the cathode and anode respectively",option:{a:"Na+ and Cl-",b:"Na+ and OH-",c:"H+ and OH-",d:"H+ and Cl-"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:70,question:"The most important use of hydrogen is in the",option:{a:"Hydrogenation of oils",b:"Manufacture of methyl alcohol",c:"Manufacture of ammonia",d:"Manufacture of ethyl alcohol"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:246,question:"Which of the following results in the fall of acid rain",option:{a:"Gaseous hydrocarbons",b:"Oxide of lead",c:"Particulate matter",d:"Oxides of sulphur"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:69,question:"Hydrogen is readily released when dilute hydrochloric acid reacts with",option:{a:"Au",b:"Cu",c:"Na",d:"Ag"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:303,question:" Two hydrocarbons X and Y were treated with bromine water. Decolorized the solution and Y did not. Which class of compound does Y belong",option:{a:"Alkynes",b:"Alkenes",c:"Alkanes",d:"Benzene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:255,question:"In the industrial production of H2 from natural gas, the CO2 produced along with the H2 is removed by",option:{a:"Passing the mixture into lime water",b:"Washing under pressure",c:"Drying over phosphorous(V)oxide",d:"Using ammoniac copper(l) chloride"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:97,question:"Which of the following will change when a catalyst is added to a chemical reaction",option:{a:"The activation energy",b:"The potential energy of the reactants",c:"The heat of reaction",d:"The potential energy of the products"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:14,question:"Environmental pollution is worsened by the release from automobile exhausts of",option:{a:"Water vapour",b:"Steam",c:"Smoke",d:"Heavy metals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:279,question:"Which of the following salts is slightly soluble in water",option:{a:"CaSO4",b:"Na2CO3",c:"PbCl2",d:"AgCl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:295,question:"Which of the following is used as fuel in miners’ lamp",option:{a:"Ethyne",b:"Ethane",c:"Ethane",d:"Ethanol"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:106,question:"Hydrogen can be displaced form a hot alkaline solution by",option:{a:"Fe",b:"Cu",c:"Ca",d:"Sn"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:209,question:"Phenolphthalein in acidic solution is",option:{a:"Colourless",b:"Yellow",c:"Red",d:"Orange"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:160,question:"Oxyacetylene flame is used for iron-welding because it",option:{a:" makes the iron metal solidity very quickly",b:"Combines with oxygen to give a pop sound",c:"Evolves a lot of heat when burnt",d:"Dissociates to produce carbon (IV) oxide and oxygen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:219,question:"Zinc and carbon rods are used as anode and cathode respectively in a",option:{a:"Voltaic cell",b:"Lead accumulator",c:"Leclanche cell",d:"Daniel cell"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:114,question:"How many isomers does pentane have",option:{a:"6",b:"5",c:"4",d:"3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:183,question:"What is the valence shell electron configuration of the element with atomic number 17",option:{a:"1s22s22p63s23p5",b:"1s22s22p63s23p4",c:"3s23p5",d:"2s22p6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:130,question:"An electron can be added to a halogen atom to form a halide ion with",option:{a:"2 valence electrons",b:"3 valence electrons",c:"7 valence electrons",d:"Valence electrons"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:120,question:"The process by which atoms are rearranged into different molecular structures in the petroleum refining process is referred to as",option:{a:"Catalytic cracking",b:"Hydrocracking",c:"Polymerization",d:"Reforming"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:167,question:` Alkanol + Alkanoic acid ⇌  Ester + water.
The reverse reaction of the equation above is known as
`,option:{a:"Hydrolysis",b:"Saponification",c:"Hydration",d:"Fermentation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:119,question:"A compound contains 40.0% carbon, 6.7% hydrogen and 53.3% oxygen. If the molar mass of the compound is 180, find the molecular formula  [H = 1, C = 12, O = 16]",option:{a:"CH2O",b:"C3H6O3",c:"C6H12O6",d:"C6H6O3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:302,question:"The haloalkanes used in the dry cleaning industries are",option:{a:"Chloroethane and dichloroethene",b:"trichloroethene and tetrachloroethene",c:"chloromethane and dichloroethene",d:"Trichloromethane and tetrachloromethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:283,question:"What quantity of aluminum is deposited when a current of 10A is passed through a solution of an aluminum salt for 1930s  {AI = 27, F = 96500 C mol-}",option:{a:"1.8g",b:"5.4g",c:"14.2g",d:"0.2g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:236,question:"If 30cm3 of a gas at 500C is warmed to 800C at a fixed pressure. The fractional increase in volume is",option:{a:"0.91",b:"0.009",c:"1.09",d:"0.093"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:65,question:"A fixed mass of gas has a  volume of 92cm3 at 30C. What will be be its volume at 180C if the pressure remains constant",option:{a:"15.3cm3",b:"87.3cm3",c:"97.0cm3",d:"552.0cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:57,question:"Three drops of a 1.0 mol dm-3 solution of Na OH are added to 20cm3 of a solution of pH8.4. the pH of the resulting solution will be",option:{a:"Greater than 8.4",b:"Unaltered",c:"Close to that of pure water",d:"Less than 8.4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:151,question:"The allotrope of carbon used in the decolourization of sugar is",option:{a:"Graphite",b:"Soot",c:"Charcoal",d:"Lampblack"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:291,question:"When iron is exposed to moist air, it gradually rusts. This is due to the formation of",option:{a:"Anahydrous  iron (III) oxide",b:"Anhydrous iron (II) oxide",c:"Hydrated iron (II) oxide",d:"Hydrated iron  (III) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:34,question:"Catalytic hydrogenation of benzene produces",option:{a:"Oil",b:"Cyclohexane",c:"Cycloexane",d:"Margarine"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:67,question:"Ordinary glass is manufactured from silica, Ca CO3 and",option:{a:"K2CO3",b:"NaHCO3",c:"Na2CO3",d:"K2SO4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:43,question:"Which of the followinig respresents hybridization in ethyne?",option:{a:"Sp2",b:"Sp2d",c:"Sp3",d:"sp"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:235,question:"The idea of planetary electrons was that of",option:{a:"Bohr",b:"Thompson",c:"Rutherford",d:"Dalton"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:227,question:"The order in which a mixture of sand ammonium chloride and sodium chloride can be separated is",option:{a:"Sublimation   dissolution  filtration  evaporation",b:"Dissolution  dryness  filtration  evaporation",c:"Filtration  sublimation  evaporation  dryness",d:"Dissolution  filtration  sublimation  evaporation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:123,question:"When a solid substance disappears completely as a gas on heating, the substance is said to have under gone",option:{a:"Evaporation",b:"Distillation",c:"Crystallization",d:"Sublimation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:198,question:"Which of the following are structural isomers",option:{a:"Propanoic acid and propan-1, 2-diol",b:"Ethanoic acid and propanoic acid",c:"Ethan-1, 2 –diol and ethanoic acid",d:"Propanal and propanone"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:170,question:"The property used in the industrial preparation of nitrogen and oxygen from air is",option:{a:"Rate of diffusion",b:"Solubility",c:"Density",d:"Boiling point"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:127,question:"According to Charles  law, the volume of a gas becomes zero at",option:{a:"00C",b:"-1000C",c:"-2730C",d:"-3730C"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"}],n={message:e,subject:o,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,t as status,o as subject,i as total};
